本期Primal Space视频由CuriosityStream赞助
This episode of Primal Space is supported by CuriosityStream.
前往curiositystream.com/primalspace即可免费观看上千部纪录片
Watch thousands of documentaries for free by visiting curiositystream.com/primalspace
2024年 太空叉打算送首批人类踏上前往火星的为期半年的征程
In 2024, SpaceX aims to send the first humans on a 6 month trip to Mars.
这趟旅程将是马一龙的“让人类成为多星球物种”目标的第一步
This journey will be the very beginning of Elon Musk's goal to make life a multiplanetary species.
为了达到这个目标 太空叉需要建立人类第一个火星基地
In order to achieve this, SpaceX will need to establish the first Martian base and -
并慢慢变成首个火星城市
over time - the first Martian city.
利用Starship火箭 数千人将能够前往火星旅行
Using their Starship rocket, thousands of people will be able to travel to Mars
并为建立首个地球外人类文明打下基础
and lay the foundation for the first human civilization outside of Earth.
但首批宇航员将如何在火星建立基地？
But how will the first astronauts establish a base on Mars?
他们将遵循怎样的法律？
And what laws will they follow?
本期视频 我们将了解在火星建立一个自给自足的城市都需要什么
In this video, we're going to look at what it will take to build a self-sustaining city on Mars.
我们还将了解火星居民将如何建构他们自己的法律体系
We're also going to look at how Martians will form their own laws
来让他们发展成繁荣的城市
in order to grow the first settlements into thriving cities.
当首批宇航员抵达火星时 他们需要一个住的地方
When the first astronauts arrive on Mars they will need a place to stay.
因为火星表面受到的辐射比地球大得多
Since the Martian surface is exposed to much more radiation than Earth,
首个火星居住舱很可能会建于地下
the first Martian habitats will most likely be built underground.
更先进的居住舱可以建在地上 外壳用厚厚的水层来抵御大多数辐射
More sophisticated habitats could be built above land with a thick layer of water to
absorb most of the radiation.
然而 运输大量的水和建造居住舱的材料价格极其昂贵
However, transporting the enormous amounts of water and materials needed to build these
habitats would be extremely expensive.
首批火星居民想要发展壮大成城市
If the first Martian habitats are to grow into large cities,
他们就必须在火星就地取材
the settlers will need to use the local materials found on Mars.
幸运的是 火星有大量有用的资源
Luckily, Mars has a large amount of useful resources.
星球表面有铁 镁和铝等金属
The surface of the planet contains metals like iron, magnesium and aluminium,
还可以从太阳获取电能
while power could be harnessed from the sun.
星球大气中存在氧气
Oxygen is present in the planet's atmosphere
星球表面下还有冰 可以提供所需的水资源
and ice buried beneath the surface could supply all the water needed.
但当宇航员开始开采这些材料的时候 开采出来的东西归谁？
But once the Martians begin mining these materials for their own use, who owns them?
1967年 美国 英国和苏联都签署了《外层空间条约》
In 1967, the US, UK and the Soviet Union all signed the Outer Space Treaty.
条约规定任何国家不得将太空或某天体据为己有
The treaty claims that no nation can claim ownership of space or a celestial body.
所以定居火星的人唯一要做的就是建立并执行规则了
It would therefore be the sole responsibility of the Martian settlers to establish and enforce rules.
但历史告诉我们 建立新的殖民地一点都不简单
But if history tells us anything, it's that creating a new colony is anything but easy.
1607年5月 104人登上詹姆士镇
In May 1607, 104 people set foot on to Jamestown.
但到了一月 就只剩38人存活了
By January, only 38 of these original settlers were still alive.
他们中许多人死于疾病与饥荒
Many of these people died from disease and famine,
还有人死于不干净的水源和部落冲突
while others passed away from toxic water and tribal warfare.
如果在地球建立新殖民地就已经很困难
If building a new settlement on Earth was tough enough,
那我们完全可以假设到另一个星球殖民更是难上加难
it's safe to assume that building one on a different planet will be even more difficult.
为了避免资源上的冲突 殖民者应该会在到达火星前就经济制度达成一致
To avoid conflicts over resources, the settlers might agree to establish an economy before arriving on Mars.
经济制度应涉及到当地资源交易内容 或者全新货币的内容
This economy could be based either on the trade of local resources, or on a brand-new currency,
这将独立于地球上已有的任何体制
independent of anything we have here on Earth.
为了保证该经济制度的公平合理
In order for this economy to be fair and balanced,
还需要一个人或者一个团体来掌管一切
it will need to be enforced - either by a group or a single person in charge of everything.
殖民者或许能够从人类在地球上犯下的错误中吸取教训
Settlers could perhaps learn from the mistakes made on Earth
制定一个更好的运营城市或国家的体制
to create a much better system for running a city or country.
“我认为火星上的政府形式最有可能是直接民主制 而不是代表民主制
“I think most likely, the form of government on Mars would be a direct democracy, not representative.
人们可以为某些问题直接投票
So it would be people voting directly on issues.
相比于代表民主制 直接民主制潜在的腐败会大幅减少
The potential for corruption is substantially diminished in a direct verses representative democracy.
移除一条法律可能比创造一个新的更简单
It should probably be easier to remove a law than to create one.
我的建议就是 比如说60%的人同意才能通过某条法律
My recommendation would be something like let's say - 60% of people need to vote in a law
但超过40%的人同意就能将其移除
but at any point greater than 40% people can remove it.
并且任何法律都应当标明有效期限”
And any law should come with a built in sunset provision.”
这样能让法律随着当前文明的进步而发展
This will help to keep the laws relevant to the current advancement of the civilization.
5到10年后 火星定居者们可以投票来通过或者废除一条法律
After 5 or 10 years, the Martians can vote if they want to pass a certain law or get rid of it.
另一个问题就是潜在的战争威胁
Another problem is the potential threat of war.
首批定居者几乎立即回遇到资源极度短缺的情况
The first settlers could face an extreme shortage of resources almost immediately
如果开采水资源的系统与种植系统没有正常运转
if the systems for mining water and growing food aren't working.
即使他们有足够的资源 离家遥远所带来的的精神摧残
Even if they have enough resources, the mental struggle of being so far from home
与强制自己适应火星生活的经历也会让一些人濒临崩溃
and committing to the Martian lifestyle could drive some settlers over the edge.
当越来越多的殖民者来到火星 他们可能会建立不同的区域 国家甚至大洲
As soon as more settlers start to arrive on Mars, they might establish different zones, countries or continents.
如果没有任何权力来监管这些不同地方的话
And without any authority to police these different places -
文明之间进步程度的不同可能会带来混乱
the varying levels of advancement between civilizations could lead to chaos.
这些只是要建立永久性殖民地所需要考虑的因素和问题的冰山一角
These are just a few of the considerations and problems that will need to be addressed
if a permanent colony is to be established.
所以尽管火星不像是那种能繁衍生息的地方
So although Mars may not seem like the kind of place to raise your kids,
但光是想想第一代火星出生的孩子们
just imagine the first generation of children born on Mars.
对于他们来说 火星才是故乡
To them, Mars is home.
他们生来就习惯了地下居住舱 沙尘暴 自家种植的食物
Underground habitats, dust storms and homegrown food is all they are used to.
对于他们来说 地球只是苍穹中漂浮的一个微小的外星世界罢了
To them, Earth is just a tiny alien world, floating in the sky.
如果你想观看更多殖民火星的内容 请来看看CuriosityStream上这个纪录片
If you'd like to watch more about colonizing Mars, check out this documentary on CuriosityStream
它介绍了在火星上建造自给自足城市背后的科学原理
- which looks at the science behind making a self-sustaining city on Mars.
CuriosityStream是一家有着无数有趣纪录片的流媒体服务网站
CuriosityStream is a streaming service with a tonne of interesting documentaries,
话题涵盖了科学 自燃 历史和科技
covering topics like: science, nature, history and technology.
CuriosityStream也有很多关于Stephen Hawking和David Attenborough的原创内容
CuriosityStream also has original content featuring the likes of Stephen Hawking and David Attenborough.
你可以前往下方连接并在注册时使用代码“primalspace”免费试用
You can watch them all for free by visiting the link below and using the code Primal Space to sign up.
一个月的试用期内可以免费观看来自世界著名电影制作人的所有纪录片和纪实文学
This will give you a month of free access to every documentary and non-fiction title, from some of the world's best filmmakers.
首月试用结束后 每月续费只需2.99美元
After your first free month, you can continue your subscription for just $2.99 a month.
所以记得关注此频道 方便我们继续一起讨论 学习所有和太空有关的知识
So make sure you're subscribed so you can join in the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
感谢观看本期视频 我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.